Encounters are mysterious! But the world is even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، والعالم تلفّه طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad I'm with you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
Today's an author mystery! Some mysteries exist outside of writing!
!قضيّة اليوم عن روائيّ غموض !توجد ألغاز خارج إطار الأوراق
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
I, Matsuda Samonji, have solved tonight's bloody string of murders!
حللتُ أنا، ماتسودا سامونجي، سلسلة جرائم !قتل الليلة الدامية
That person is undoubtedly the killer!
المجرم هو ذاك الشخص بلا شكّ
Detective Samonji
المتحرّي سامونجي
The son! The son! The son did it!
!الابن! الابن! المجرم هو الابن
That's dumb! The son is a fake! It's the wife of the murdered man!
حمقاء، الابن تمويه، والفاعل الحقيقيّ هي زوجة الرجل المقتول
Who do you think did it, Conan-kun?
من تظنّه الفاعل يا كونان-كن؟
I'll say the same person as you!
سأختار نفس الشخص مثلك
See! Even he thinks so!
!رأيت! كونان-كن يوافقني
How would he know? Kids don't know anything!
هذا مجرّد تفكير أطفال سطحيّ
The killer...
...القاتل
...is you, his son!
!هو أنت
I knew it!
!كما ظننت
That's impossible!
!مستحيل
It was different the last time I saw it...
...في المرّة السابقة التي شاهدته فيها، كان
The Detective Samonji series is always being remade,
يُعاد إنتاج سلسلة المتحرّي سامونجي هذه عدّة مرّات
and the killer changes each time!
والقاتل يتغيّر كلّ مرة
That's why it's always so interesting!
!لذا تبقى مسليّة مهما شاهدتها
You blockhead!
!يا أحمق
What was that for?! Don't make me mad!
!لمَ فعلت هذا فجأةً؟! لا تغضبني
That's not mad!
أيّ غضب هذا؟
What are you doing, Dad?!
!ما الذي تفعله يا أبي؟
Quick-draw detective, my butt! How pathetic!
المتحرّي سريع الاستلال"؟" يا للسخافة"
Turn it back! Samonji's about to pull out his sword and say a haiku!
أرجع القناة! سامونجي على وشك استسلال !سيفه وإلقاء قصيدة هايكو للقاتل
Too bad!
!كلا، كلا
Come on! Turn it back! It's going to end!
!لمَ؟! أرجع جهاز التحكّم فوراً! سينتهي
Things sure are peaceful for father and daughter to argue over this...
يا للأجواء المسالمة ليتشاجر الأب وابنته في أشياء كهذه
So many people have fallen victim to their organization.
تسبّبت منظمتهم بوقوع الكثير من الضحايا
But nobody realizes it's the organization's fault.
لكن لم يدرك أحد بعد أنّها أفعال المنظمة
If I want to be normal again,
،إذا أردت العودة لجسدي الطبيعيّ
I have to turn this bumbling detective into a real master detective
فعليّ تحويل هذا المتحرّي تائه السبيل لمتحرٍّ حقيقي
and obtain information on the men in black's organization!
وأن أحصل على معلومات عن منظمتهم
If he gets more work, I'll eventually run into a case involving them!
،إذا ارتفع عدد العملاء الذين يتلقّاهم فلا بدّ أن تمر قضيّة تتعلّق بهم
If I continue to seek the truth, I know I can do it!
،إذا واصلتُ السعي وراء الحقيقة هكذا ...فلا بدّ، لا بدّ أنّي
Now it's over!
انتهى الآن
What's so good about it anyway? He's just a third-rate detective.
ما المثير فيه بأيّ حال؟ إنّه مجرد متحرٍّ من الطراز الثالث
So says the dimwitted detective...
هذا ما يقوله المتحرّي البليد
Besides, the original series ended long ago.
،كما أنّ السلسلة الأصليّة انتهت قبل وقتٍ طويل
It's annoying that they keep putting it on TV.
!فلمَ يعرضونه باستمرار على التلفاز؟ يا للإزعاج
Let's see. I'm sure it's around here.
حسناً، كانت هنا كما أظنّ
Literature Era started it two months ago.
..."قبل شهرين في "عصر الأدب
See!
انظرا
"Shinmei Nintaro's highly anticipated 'Detective Samonji' returns!"
عودة (المتحرّي سامونجي) لـ شينمي نينتارو" "!التي يترقّبها الجميع
Seriously?!
!حقّاً؟
This takes me back!
!هذا يشعرني بالحنين
He and a killer disappeared into a fire ten years ago,
،اختفى مع القاتل في النار قبل 10 أعوام
but I guess he survived!
لكنّه كان حيّاً إذاً؟
It takes you back?
بالحنين؟
That's what Shinichi-niichan said on the phone the other day...
هذا ما قاله شينتشي-نيتشان ...على الهاتف ذاك اليوم
Shinichi did?
شينتشي؟
That mystery nerd, huh...
مهووس التحرّي ذاك؟
Oh? I think someone's at your office downstairs...
ماذا؟ يبدو أنّ هناك عميلاً عند المكتب في الأسفل
Yeah, tell them it's late and to come back tomorrow.
أجل، أخبريه أنّ الوقت تأخّر لذا فليأت غداً
Okay.
حسناً، حسناً
I'm sorry! The office is closed for the day!
المعذرة، المكتب مقفل الآن
But I really do need to talk to Detective Mori about something.
لكنّي بحاجة ملحّة لاستشارة المتحرّي موري في شيء
Could he at least hear what I have to say?
هل يمكنه الاستماع لي على الأقل؟
Hottie!
!حسناء
It's rather late, so could you come back tomorrow?
لكن الوقت تأخّر، لذا هلّا أتيتِ مُجدداً في الغد؟
Wait, wait, wait!
!انتظري، انتظري، انتظري
What are you saying to our guest?!
!ما الذي تقولينه لعميلتنا؟
Sorry to keep you waiting! I am Mori Kogoro!
!آسفٌ على الإطالة! أنا موري كوغورو
I apologize for my rude daughter!
اعذري ابنتي الفظّة
Please! Come right in!
هيّا، تفضّلي بالدخول
Thank you.
شكراً
Right this way!
هيّا
What's with that attitude? You told me to turn her away!
ما هذا السلوك؟ أنت من أخبرني بردّها
Please, have a seat!
هيّا، تفضّلي بالجلوس
My apologies! Go right ahead!
المعذرة، تفضّلي
Thank you.
شكراً
It's nothing special, but...
...مجرّد شاي، لكن
Now, then. May I ask what brings you here?
إذاً، هلّا أخبرتِني بطلبك؟
Yes. My name is Shinmei Kaori.
...أجل، أنا
Shinmei? You don't mean--?!
...شينمي؟ أيمكن
The mystery writer's--?
...روائيّ الغموض
Shinmei Kaori (22), office worker
أجل، شينمي نينتارو أبي
Yes. Shinmei Nintaro is my father.
(شينمي كاوري (22 موظّفة شركة
You're the daughter of that great master?!
!أنتِ ابنة ذاك المعلّم المبجّل إذاً؟
I can never get enough of Samonji's haikus!
!لا أسأم من هايكو سامونجي مهما سمعت منها
Right?!
أليس كذلك؟
So, how can I help you? Does he want to use me in a novel?
إذاً، كيف أساعدك؟ أيريد منّي الظهور في رواية؟
No, actually... my father has been missing for two months.
...لا، في الواقع
He's...
مفقود؟
That is quite--
...هذا
Don't be silly!
ما الذي تقولينه؟
He's been writing serials for Literature Era for the past two months!
"كان يكتب سلسلةً لـ "عصر الأدب !للشهرين الفائتين
But it's the truth! He and my mother disappeared from their home!
!لكنّها الحقيقة! اختفى من المنزل مع أمّي
Y-Your mother, too?
مـ-مع أمّك؟
They both vanished about one week before this serialization began.
اختفيا قبل قرابة أسبوع من بدء السلسلة الحاليّة
I checked with all our relatives and acquaintances of course,
،سألتُ أقاربنا ومعارفنا بالطبع
but no one knew anything.
لكن لم يعرف أحدٌ شيئاً
Still, don't his serials mean that he is writing manuscripts?
لكن ألا تعني السلسلة أنّه يكتب النصوص؟
Yes.
أجل
Oddly enough, the manuscripts are faxed to the editing department.
لغرابة الأمر، تُرسل النصوص بالفاكس لدائرة التحرير
Every Saturday, at exactly midnight.
كلّ سبت في منتصف الليل تماماً
But don't the faxes have the sender's phone number or anything?
لـ-لكن ألا تحمل رسائل الفاكس تلك رقم هاتف المرسل وما شابه؟
No, nothing at all.
كلا، لا شيء
It seems the sender has it configured not to display those things.
يبدو أنّ المرسل ضبطها بحيث لا تعرض تلك الأشياء
Hmm...
...حسناً
It's probably because he and his wife are on vacation somewhere
...لعلّه
and he sends the faxes from the hotel they're staying at!
ويرسل الفاكس من الفندق الذي يقطنان فيه
I thought so too at first!
ذلك ما ظننتُه بدايةً
But they've never been quiet for two months like this before!
لكن لم يسبق أن يقطعا !تواصلهما معي لشهرين هكذا
I can only think that something happened!
!لا يسعني سوى التفكير أنّ أمراً ما حلّ بهما
Did you contact the police?
هلّ اتّصلتِ بالشرطة؟
Yes.
أجل
I asked them to investigate, but there had been no ransom calls
قدّمت طلب تحقيق لهم، لكن لم ترد مكالمات فدية
and the manuscripts were being sent, so they said not to worry.
والنصوص تُرسل، فأخبروني أنّ لا داعي للقلق
I tried the other detective agencies, but they all said the same thing.
،جرّبتُ الذهاب لوكالات التحرّي الأخرى لكنّهم قالوا جميعاً الأمر نفسه
You're my last hope, Mori-san!
هذا أملي الأخير
This is pointless!
لا فائدة
We're only wasting time by sitting here!
نحن نهدر وقتنا بالجلوس هنا
Let's check the editing department where his manuscripts get sent!
لنذهب لدائرة التحرير التي تتلقّى النصوص
You can save your troubles for after that!
يمكنك تأجيل قلقك لبعد ذلك
R-Right!
!أ-أجل
Taxi!
!تاكسي
After you!
تفضّلي
Yes, Shinmei-sensei's manuscripts get sent here every week.
أجل، تصلنا نصوص شينمي سينسي أسبوعياً
Daigakukan
دايغاكوكان
More should be sent today, at any time now...
الليلة هي الموعد المعتاد، يُفترض أن تُرسل قريباً
Are these manuscripts really written by him?
أتلك النصوص من تأليفه حقّاً؟
Yes. Although they're typed out, the words are most definitely his!
أجل، إنّها مطبوعة،  لكن أسلوب الكتابة يخصّه بلا شكّ
He signs his name next to the title each time, too.
ويوقّع باسمه بجوار العنوان كلّ مرّة أيضاً
I can show you the faxed manuscripts, if you'd like.
يمكنني أن أريكم فاكس النصّ إذا أردتم
Halves at the Top
نصفان في القمّة
The title is "Halves at the Top"?
العنوان هو "نصفان في القمّة" إذاً؟
And he's signed them, too.
وتوقيعه موجود أيضاً
Are you certain this is his signature?
أأنتِ متأكّدة أنّ هذا توقيعه؟
Yes. We confirmed it when I came here earlier.
أجل، فقد تأكّدت منه عندما أتيت هنا قبلاً
There's nothing to worry about, Kaori-san!
لا تقلقي يا كاوري-سان
I'm sure he's just so focused on writing that he forgot to contact you.
لا بدّ أنّه منهمك بالكتابة ونسي التواصل معك
The same thing happens to lots of other writers!
!هذا شائعٌ بين الروائيين
But are you sure he forgot? His wife's with him...
لكن أنسي حقّاً؟ فزوجته معه
Yeah, now that you mention it...
...حسناً، بذكرك ذلك
Did he seem different in any way?
هل بدا عليه أيّ اختلاف؟
Different?
اختلاف؟
You know, like during a meeting or something.
تجرون اجتماعات، أليس كذلك؟
Yes, we had a simple meeting before we started the serials,
،بلى، أجرينا اجتماعاً بسيطاً قبل بدئنا السلسلة
but he didn't seem any different...
لكن لم يبد عليه اختلاف محدّد
Anything at all? Even the tiniest thing might help...
أيمكنك التذكّر؟ أيّ شيء بسيط قد يفيد
I suppose there is the fact he restarted his Detective Samonji series.
إذا كنتُ سأذكر شيئاً، فهو إكماله لسلسلة المتحرّي سامونجي هذه
Huh?
ماذا؟
You see, I have been asking him to restart this series for the past four years.
في الواقع، كنتُ ألحّ عليه بإكمال هذه السلسلة للأربعة أعوام الفائتة
But he always answered by saying...
لكن كان ردّه ثابتاً
Samonji is dead. There's no bringing him back.
"سامونجي ميت، لا يمكن أن أعيده للحياة"
So I had half given up when he suddenly called two months ago
ما قاله، فكنتُ مستسلماً تقريباً حتّى اتّصل فجأةً قبل شهرين
to ask if we could make room for his new Samonji series.
وسألنا إذا ما نستطيع توفير مساحة في المجلة بما أنّه يريد إكمال سامونجي
We were more than happy to oblige, of course,
سرّنا قبول ذلك بالطبع
so we hurriedly canceled the new series we were running
وألغينا السلسلة الجديدة التي حدّدناها في عجلة
and replaced it with Samonji.
واستبدلناها بسامونجي
I see. Anything else?
فهمت، أيّ شيءٍ آخر؟
but for the dedication, he wrote this:
:لكنّه كتب التالي في صفحة الإهداء في السلسلة
"Attention, all master detectives throughout Japan!
،إلى كلّ متحرّيي البلاد المرموقين"
If you wish to surpass my intellect, solve this case's true mystery."
إذا أردتم تخطّي حنكتي، فحلّوا لغز !هذه القضيّة الحقيقيّ
That's quite a provocative dedication.
يا للإهداء المشعّ تحدياً
Yes. And ever since the first chapter, we've received
أجل، وأصبحنا نتلقى رسائل ومكالمات من المعجبين منذ الفصل الأوّل
tons of calls and fan letters saying, "This is how it was done!"
"!بـ "هذا الشخص مريب!" و"هكذا هي الحيلة
As an editor, it makes me happy,
الأمر يسعدني بصفتي المحرّر
but it seemed like a rare move for such a mild-mannered writer.
لكنّي رأيتها بادرة نادرة من روائيّ خلوق مثله
Though, fans have been waiting like crazy for over ten years,
رغم أنّه عمل جديد لسلسلة كان المعجبون بانتظارها بإلحاح لعشرة أعوام
so it's only natural he's getting such a big reception.
فمن الطبيعيّ أن يكون التفاعل مرتفعاً
"Like crazy"?
بإلحاح؟
Yes, there was even a scary call last year from a crazed fan
أجل، وصل الأمر بحيث تلقّينا اتّصالاً مخيفاً من معجب مجنون العام الفائت
who threatened to set this place on fire if he didn't restart the series!
يهدّدنا فيه بإضرام الحريق في المكان إذا لم نكمل السلسلة
Talk about extreme...
يا للتطرّف
Oh, yes! There's one other thing that seemed strange!
صحيح، صحيح، هنالك أمرٌ غريب آخر
He appears in his own novel!
ظهر سينسي في روايته
Come again?
ماذا؟
Shinmei-sensei appears in the story, as an old friend of Samonji's!
يظهر شينمي سينسي في القصّة بصفته صديقاً قديماً لسامونجي
He's a struggling writer who resides in France.
في إطار روائيّ غير ناجح يقيم في فرنسا
There are about forty stories in the series, but this is a first!
،تتألّف السلسلة من قرابة 40 كتاباً لكن هذا الأمر غير مسبوق
I think it's going to end with all the previous cases
أظنّه سيختتم القصّة بكون كلّ القضايا السابقة
being things Samonji told him about!
أشياء أخبره سامونجي عنها
Kind of like how Watson is to Sherlock Holmes!
مثل وضع واتسون بالنسبة لشارلوك هولمز
Say! Could you show me that scene?
أيمكنك أن تريني ذاك المشهد؟
Sure!
!أجل، بالطبع
But can you read kanji, little boy?
لكن أيمكنك قراءة الكانجي يا فتى؟
A little!
قليلاً
Shinmei-sensei makes his first appearance
يحقّق شينمي سينسي ظهوره الأوّل
when Samonji calls a friend living in France for advice on a case.
عندما يتّصل سامونجي بصديق يعيش في فرنسا لاستشارته في قضيّة
His character is absentminded and funny!
!شخصيته متحامقة وطريفة
W-What's this?!
...هـ-هذا
This is strange!
!هذا غريب
Look at this!
انظروا
10:00 is written in kanji here, but 1:00 is written with a number!
،العاشرة في "12" مكتوبة هنا بالكانجي لكن "1" مكتوبٌ كرقم
This guy must've been pretty tired, huh?
لا بدّ أنّه كان متعباً جدّاً
That is strange. Could this actually be...
...هذا غريب بالفعل، أيمكن أّنّه
...a misprint on your part?
خطأ... في الطباعة لديكم؟
No!
!كلا
We wanted to fix it to make it easier to read, too!
،أردنا إصلاحها لتسهيل القراءة أيضاً
But he said, "The lay of the letters is a novel's life! Don't change it!"
لكنّه قال "تنظيم الأحرف هو بمثابة "حياة الرواية! لا تغيّروه أبداً
He said it many times before the serialization.
ردّد هذا مراراً قبل بدء السلسلة
He also said he'd cancel the series immediately if we defied his wish.
كما قال أنّه سيلغي السلسلة فوراً إذا نشرنا شيئاً يخالف إرادته
Then that makes it all the odder.
هذا يثير الغرابة أكثر
It's almost as if something is being hidden in the writing.
كما لو أنّ هنالك شيئاً مخفيّاً في هذا العمل
And then there are Shinmei-sensei's signatures.
وما يثير حيرتي هو توقيع شينمي سينسي الخطّي
If my theory is correct, it's possible that he's already...
إذا أصاب استنتاجي، ففي أسوأ الأحوال ...لعلّه بالفعل فارق
Oh! Here's his latest fax!
!ها هو! فاكس سينسي
Let's see here...
...لنرَ
You can't look yet!
!لا يمكنك النظر بعد
It's a mystery story! Wait until it's in book form to read it!
إنّها رواية غموض، انتظر نشرها في الكتاب لقراءتها
Hey!
!مهلك
I thought so!
!كما ظننت
Hey, you!
أنت! ما الذي تفعله؟
But his signature is weird!
لكنّ توقيعه غريب
Chapters six through eight match perfectly.
إنّه متطابق من الفصل السادس حتّى الثامن
Nintaro
نينتارو
Th-They do!
مـ-معك حقّ
Chapters one through six are all slightly different, though. I wonder why!
توقيع الفصول من الأوّل حتّى السادس مختلف قليلاً، فلمَ يا ترى؟
He obviously just copied an earlier signature.
من الجلّي أنّه نسخ توقيعاً سابقاً
Why would he do that?
ولمَ قد يفعل ذلك؟
Because he didn't want to write it anymore...
...لأنّه لم يعد يريد الكتابة
...or he couldn't anymore?
أو لم يعد يستطيع؟
Mori-san!
!موري-سان
If he can't write anymore,
،إذا لم يعد يستطيع الكتابة
that means Shinmei-sensei might already be dead, doesn't it?
فلربما فارق شينمي سينسي الحياة سلفاً، أليس كذلك؟
Y-You can't be serious!
!لا-لا يمكن
This is bad! This requires immediate action!
!هذا سيّئ! لا بدّ من تدخّل عاجل
You! The police! Call the police!
!أنت! اتّصل بالشرطة! الشرطة
Right!
!حاضر
It's not 100% yet! There's a chance he's still alive!
ليس الأمر مؤكّداً، هنالك فرصة ببقائه على قيد الحياة
The key to saving his life is probably hidden inside this novel!
مفتاح إنقاذ حياته هو هذه الرواية غالباً
As a message he's left for us detectives!
!رسالة تركها لنا نحن المتحرّيين
You can't open an investigation?
لا يمكنكم بدء تحقيق رسميّ؟
No, we still can't. Not at this stage.
أجل، ليس في هذه المرحلة
Hold on, Inspector!
!مهلك رجاءً حضرة المفتّش
Shinmei Nintaro, her father and a mystery writer,
والد كاوري-سان وروائيّ التحرّي الشهير شينمي نينتارو
has been missing for two months now!
!مفقود لشهرين الآن
What's more, his wife is also gone!
!كما أنّ زوجته مفقودة معه
I can only think they got caught up in some sort of incident!
لا يسعني التفكير سوى بأنّهما !علقا في حادثة ما
Even so, his manuscripts are being faxed here every single week.
لكنّ نصوصه تُرسل إلى دائرة التحرير هذه بالفاكس أسبوعياً
Even though they're faxes,
،رغم أنّه فاكس
his daughter and the editors all agree it's his writing!
الابنة والمحرّرون مجمعون على أنّ هذه كتابته
And like I said, those faxes are the issue here!
!لكن كما قلت، المشكلة هي نصوص الفاكس هذه
Don't those signatures seem strange to you?!
ألا تجد التواقيع غريبة؟
Signatures? But they were already confirmed to be his.
التواقيع؟ لكن تمّ تأكيد أنّها للسيّد شينمي
Between Chapter one and six, his signatures are all slightly different,
تواقيعه التي بجوار العنوان من الفصل ،الأوّل حتّى السادس بها اختلاف جميعها
but between Chapter six and eight, they're all exactly the same!
!لكنّها متطابقة من الفصل السادس للثامن
They're obviously copies of a previous signature
إنّها منسوخة من التوقيع السابق بلا شكّ
and evidence that he's now in a condition in which he can't write!
وبرهانٌ على أنّه في حالة لا تسمح له بالكتابة حالياً
In other words, something has happened to him!
!مما يعني أنّ أمراً ما حلّ به
Then tell me... Who did what to Mr. Shinmei?
أخبرني إذاً، من فعل ماذا لـ شينمي-سان؟
I'd believe you more if there was a threatening phone call,
كنتُ لأقتنع بكلامك أكثر لو ورد اتّصال تهديد وما شابه
but there's been nothing at all.
لكن لم يرد شيء حتّى الآن
Besides, maybe he got sick of signing them and used copies instead.
كما لعلّه سئم من التوقيع كلّ مرّة وقرر استعمال النسخ
True. Given the circumstances, Inspector Megure is right.
بالفعل، المفتّش ميغوري على حقّ بالنظر للظروف
It wouldn't be surprising for an eccentric writer
ليس غريباً في المرحلة الحالية ذهاب روائيّ غريب الطباع
to take his wife and hole up somewhere to focus on his writing.
مع زوجته لعزل نفسيهما في مكان للتركيز على الكتابة
But something bugs me!
لكن هناك ما يضايقني
Attention, all master detectives throughout Japan!
!إلى كلّ متحرّيي البلاد المرموقين
It wasn't like him to write that dedication.
ذاك التحدّي الذي لا يوافق صفاته في صفحة الإهداء
It was very extreme and provocative for someone so mild-mannered.
كان متطرّفاً واستفزازياً بالنسبة لرجل خلوق مثله
Then, there's the fact the writer suddenly appears in the series.
كما هناك ظهور المؤلف الأوّل المفاجئ في السلسلة
And then there's his odd dialogue
وهذا الحوار الغريب
that mixes numbers, kanji numbers, and English letters...
الذي يخلط الأرقام العددية وأرقام الكانجي والأحرف الإنجليزية
If my theory is correct,
،إذا أصاب استنتاجي
there must be a message from Shinmei-sensei in here!
فيُفترض أنّ هنالك رسالة من شينمي سينسي بين ثنايا هذه الجمل
Inspector! I made copies of all the lines Mori-san was curious about.
حضرة المفتّش، نسخت كلّ الأسطر التي أثارت حفيظة موري-سان
Mr. Shinmei makes four appearances so far?
ظهر السيّد شينمي أربع مرّات للآن؟
Can I have a copy, too?
هلّا أعطيتني نسخة؟
Stop that! Don't get in the way!
!كلا! لا تتدخّل
It's okay! There are extras!
لا بأس، توجد نسخ إضافيّة
Here you go!
هاك
Thank you!
!شكراً لك
Let's see, his first appearance is when the main detective character
حسناً، كان ظهوره الأوّل عندما اتّصل البطل المتحرّي
calls Mr. Shinmei, who is residing in France.
بالسيّد شينمي المقيم في فرنسا
He's also in France the second time...
وهو في فرنسا في المرّة الثانية أيضاً
He's in France the third time...
...وكذلك فرنسا في المرّة الثالثة
And the fourth time, too.
والمرّة الرابعة أيضاً
Does Mr. Shinmei like France?
هل يحبّ السيّد شينمي فرنسا؟
Yes. He and my mother often traveled there.
أجل، اعتاد السفر لها مع أمّي
Damn! Reading them backwards or rearranging them doesn't work!
تبّاً! حتّى القراءة بالمقلوب !وإعادة الترتيب لا تعطي شيئاً
If only I had a point to start from!
...لو، لو امتلكت نقطة بداية
Umm, do you mind if we use Chapter eight of "Halves at the Top,"
المعذرة، أتمانع لو استعملنا نصّ الفصل الثامن من "نصفان في القمّة
the manuscript he just faxed?
الذي أرسله سينسي قبل قليل؟
Halves at the top?
نصفان في القمّة؟
It's the title of the work you're reading right now!
بربّك، إنّه عنوان العمل الذي تقرؤه الآن
Halves at the--?
...نصفان في
Halves at the top?!
!نصفان في القمّة؟
Hold on, now! Could this actually be--?!
...انتظر، أيمكن... أيمكن أنّ هذه
T-This is--!
!هـ-هذا
Just as I thought!
!كما ظننت
There's a message from Shinmei-sensei hidden in these lines!
توجد رسالة مخفية من شينمي سينسي !بين هذه الأسطر
Which makes it all fit: that provocative dedication,
في تلك الحالة، ذاك الإهداء الاستفزازي وظهور المؤلّف في العمل
the author's appearance in the story, and the odd lines of dialogue!
!والحوار الغريب، كلّها تتوافق
But what is the goal of the person holding him and his wife captive?!
لكن ما هدف الفاعل الذي يحتجز !شينمي سينسي وزوجته؟
Inspector!
!حضرة المفتّش
What is it, Takagi-kun?
ما الأمر يا تاكاغي-كن؟
Look at this manuscript! There's more dialogue!
انظر لهذا النصّ، لا يزال هنالك حوار
Huh? This is the eighth chapter that was just faxed here?
ماذا؟ هذا الفصل الثامن الذي أُرسل للتوّ؟
"Hurry..."
"أسرعوا"
"There's..."
"الوقت"
"...no time..."
"ينفد"
"Hurry, there's no time!"
"بسرعة، الوقت ينفد"
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
"The Mystery Writer Disappearance Case (Part 2)."
جريمة اختفاء مؤلف روايات الغموض (الجزء الثاني)
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
French language.
لغة فرنسيّة
Message from author Aoyama-sensei.
لدينا رسالة من المؤلف آوياما سينسي
What'd he say? That he likes this segment?
ماذا؟ أيقول أنّ هذا الركن ناجح؟